<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Minor</h3>
<p>The Science and Math Education minor is offered by the Cal Teach program. Cal Teach is a program for undergraduate STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) majors interested in exploring a career in education.</p>
<p>Cal Teach at UC Berkeley is working to increase the number of qualified STEM educators in K-12 classrooms. Courses in the Cal Teach program are open to any STEM major with a desire to promote math and science education and equity.</p>
<p>Cal Teach is unique from other education programs in that is focused on learning and applying those skills in local classrooms. All the courses in the Science and Math Education minor have <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/cal-teach-program/field-placements.php" target="_blank">field placements</a>
 in local K-12 STEM classrooms. By the time students graduate with the minor they will have spent over 100 hours honing their teaching in local classrooms. </p>

<p>The Cal Teach program is unique in that it offers STEM students the unique opportunity to complete both a bachelor’s degree and a California teaching credential as an undergraduate. So while, UC Berkeley does not offer a major in Education, earning your <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/cal-teach-program/cal-teach-credential.php" target="_blank">teaching credential and minor with Cal Teach</a>
 is as close as you can get.</p>

<p>The courses in the Science and Math Education minor cover topics including inquiry-based learning, creating and assessing student learning outcomes, equity in urban education, project-based instruction, methods of conducting and presenting research, and positive teacher-student interactions. The knowledge and skills gained in these courses are integral to success in any field that requires the communication of knowledge to others. This includes, but is not limited to, education, business, scientific/engineering industry, and public service.</p>
<p>Additional <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/scholarships-and-opportunities/" target="_blank">scholarships, internships, and research opportunities</a>
 are provided to students in the Cal Teach minor. </p>

<h3><span class="s1">Applying for the Minor</span></h3>
<p>It is recommended to schedule a meeting with the Cal Teach student adviser to discuss your planning and educational goals as early as possible. Learn more about advising resources <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/cal-teach-program/advising-and-resources.php" target="_blank">here</a>
.</p>

<p>After completing the introductory course and all five upper division minor courses, speak with the student adviser about completing the appropriate paperwork to be awarded the minor.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<minorrequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<p>The minor in Science and Math Education demonstrates a passion and excellence in K-12 STEM Education. Additionally earning the Science and Math minor allows you to apply to the Cal Teach science and math credential program, allowing students to earn their California Teaching Credential.</p>
<p>To learn more, schedule or plan, and to declare the minor please schedule an appointment with the <a href="http://calteach.berkeley.edu/cal-teach-program/advising-and-resources.php" target="_blank">Cal Teach Student Adviser. </a>
 </p>

<h3>Guidelines</h3>
<ol>
	<li>Enroll in and complete <span class="sc_courseinline">UGIS&#160;82 K-8 Teaching and Inquiry-Based Lesson Design in the Science and Mathematics Classroom</span>.</li>

	<li>Speak with the Cal Teach student adviser about fitting the courses for the minor into your schedule.</li>
	<li>The minor in Science and Math Education requires five courses:</li>
</ol>

<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><colgroup><col class="codecol" /><col class="titlecol" /><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol" /></colgroup><tbody><tr class="even areaheader firstrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment areaheader">Required Courses</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Take these three courses in sequence after completing UGIS&#160;82:</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">EDUC&#160;130</td><td>Knowing and Learning in Mathematics and Science</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">EDUC&#160;131</td><td>Classroom Interactions in Science and Mathematics: A Focus on Equity and Urban Schools</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">UGIS&#160;187</td><td>Project-Based Instruction</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Complete the following two courses at any point after completing UGIS&#160;82 and before the completion of your bachelor's degree:</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td class="codecol">UGIS&#160;188</td><td>Research Methods for Science and Mathematics K-12 Teachers</td><td class="hourscol">3</td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td class="codecol">HISTORY&#160;138T</td><td>History of Science in the US CalTeach <sup>1</sup></td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass odd lastrow"><td class="codecol orclass">or&#160;HISTORY&#160;180T</td><td colspan="2"> History of the Life Sciences Since 1750 (Cal Teach)</td></tr>
<tr class="orclass odd lastrow"><td class="codecol orclass">or&#160;HISTORY&#160;182AT</td><td colspan="2"> Science, Technology, and Society (Cal Teach)</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<table border="0" width="100%" class="sc_footnotes"><tr><td valign="top" class="symcol"><sup>1</sup></td><td class="notecol"><p>The course offered varies by semester. Check <a href="The course offered varies by semester. Check schedule.berkeley.edu for which course is offered in the upcoming semester." target="_blank">http://schedule.berkeley.edu</a> for which course is offered in the upcoming semester.</p></td></tr></table>
]]>
</minorrequirementstext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

