<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<abouttheprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>The MA in Latin American Studies is a two-year program that allows students to pursue a diverse curriculum in Latin American Studies spanning a wide range of departments and professional schools, including the schools of Natural Resources, Public Health, Public Policy, Social Welfare, Journalism, Law, Education, and Environmental Design.</p>
<p>Students begin by taking courses that offer a broad overview of the field of Latin American Studies and introduce them to Latin Americanist research at Berkeley. Students then work closely with individual faculty to define their particular areas of interest and research.</p>
<p>The MA program provides an opportunity for collective learning and collaboration as students develop research skills and specialized knowledge in the field. Students are encouraged to draw on the considerable resources of the Center for Latin American Studies.</p>
]]>
</abouttheprogramtext>
<admissionstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1">Admission to the University</h3>
 <h4>Minimum Requirements for Admission</h4> <p>The following minimum requirements apply to all graduate programs and will be verified by the Graduate Division:</p> <ol> 	<li>A bachelor’s degree or recognized equivalent from an accredited institution;</li> 	<li>A grade point average of B or better (3.0);</li> 	<li>If the applicant comes from a country or political entity (e.g., Quebec) where English is not the official language, adequate proficiency in English to do graduate work, as evidenced by a TOEFL score of at least 90 on the iBT test, 570 on the paper-and-pencil test, 230 on the computer-based test, or an IELTS Band score of at least 7 (note that individual programs may set higher levels for any of these); and</li> 	<li>Sufficient undergraduate training to do graduate work in the given field.</li> </ol> <h4>Applicants Who Already Hold a Graduate Degree</h4> <p>The Graduate Council views academic degrees not as vocational training certificates but as evidence of broad training in research methods, independent study, and articulation of learning. Therefore, applicants who already have academic graduate degrees should be able to pursue new subject matter at an advanced level without need to enroll in a related or similar graduate program.</p> <p>Programs may consider students for an additional academic master’s or professional master’s degree only if the additional degree is in a distinctly different field.</p> <p>Applicants admitted to a doctoral program that requires a master’s degree to be earned at Berkeley as a prerequisite (even though the applicant already has a master’s degree from another institution in the same or a closely allied field of study) will be permitted to undertake the second master’s degree, despite the overlap in field.</p> <p>The Graduate Division will admit students for a second doctoral degree only if they meet the following guidelines:</p> <ol> 	<li>Applicants with doctoral degrees may be admitted for an additional doctoral degree only if that degree program is in a general area of knowledge distinctly different from the field in which they earned their original degree. For example, a physics PhD could be admitted to a doctoral degree program in music or history; however, a student with a doctoral degree in mathematics would not be permitted to add a PhD in statistics.</li> 	<li>Applicants who hold the PhD degree may be admitted to a professional doctorate or professional master’s degree program if there is no duplication of training involved.</li> </ol> <p>Applicants may apply only to one single degree program or one concurrent degree program per admission cycle.</p> <p>Any applicant who was previously registered at Berkeley as a graduate student, no matter how briefly, must apply for readmission, not admission, even if the new application is to a different program.</p> <h4>Required Documents for Applications</h4> <ol> 	<li><strong>Transcripts:  </strong>Applicants may u<span>pload <em>unofficial </em>transcripts with your application for the departmental initial review. <em>If the applicant is admitted,</em> then <em>official </em>transcripts of all college-level work will be required. Admitted applicants must r</span>equest a current transcript from every post-secondary school attended, including community colleges, summer sessions, and extension programs. <span>Official transcripts must be in sealed envelopes as issued by the school(s) attended. </span> 	<div class="gmail_default">If you have attended Berkeley, upload your unofficial transcript with your application for the departmental initial review. <em>If you are admitted,</em> an official transcript with evidence of degree conferral <em>will not</em> be required.</div> 	</li> 	<li><strong>Letters of recommendation:</strong> Applicants may request online letters of recommendation through the online application system. Hard copies of recommendation letters must be sent directly to the program, not the Graduate Division.</li> 	<li><strong>Evidence of English language proficiency:</strong> All applicants from countries or political entities in which the official language is not English are required to submit official evidence of English language proficiency. This applies to applicants from Bangladesh, Burma, Nepal, India, Pakistan, Latin America, the Middle East, the People’s Republic of China, Taiwan, Japan, Korea, Southeast Asia, most European countries, and Quebec (Canada). However, applicants who, at the time of application, have already completed at least one year of full-time academic course work with grades of B or better at a US university may submit an official transcript from the US university to fulfill this requirement. The following courses will not fulfill this requirement: 1) courses in English as a Second Language, 2) courses conducted in a language other than English, 3) courses that will be completed after the application is submitted, and 4) courses of a non-academic nature. If applicants have previously been denied admission to Berkeley on the basis of their English language proficiency, they must submit new test scores that meet the current minimum from one of the standardized tests.</li> </ol> <h4>Where to Apply</h4> <p>Visit the Berkeley Graduate Division <a href="http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/apply/" target="_blank">application page</a> . </p> 
]]>
</admissionstext>
<mastersdegreerequirementstext>
<![CDATA[
<h3 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Curriculum</h3>
<table class="sc_courselist" width="100%"><colgroup><col class="codecol" /><col class="titlecol" /><col align="char" char="." class="hourscol" /></colgroup><tbody><tr class="even firstrow"><td class="codecol">LATAMST&#160;200</td><td>Latin American Studies Seminar</td><td class="hourscol">1</td></tr>
<tr class="odd"><td class="codecol">LATAMST&#160;250</td><td>Selected Topics in Latin American Studies</td><td class="hourscol">4</td></tr>
<tr class="even"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Graduate elective in Methods</span></td><td class="hourscol"></td></tr>
<tr class="odd lastrow"><td colspan="2"><span class="courselistcomment">Minimum of 20-24 units of electives, as per approved study list, concentrated in 2-3 disciplines</span></td><td class="hourscol">20-24</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<h3 class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Foreign Language</h3>
<p class="Normal1CxSpMiddle">Students must demonstrate a high level of proficiency in their chosen primary language (either Spanish or Portuguese) and must demonstrate strong reading and speaking skills in their secondary language.</p>
]]>
</mastersdegreerequirementstext>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Latin American Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
<div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=LATAMST 200" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="91">
<span class="code">LATAMST&#160;200</span> 
<span class="title">Latin American Studies Seminar</span> 
<span class="hours">1 Unit</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2017, Fall 2016, Fall 2015<br/>
Mandatory for Latin American Studies graduate students. Seminars by faculty and advanced graduate students on their current research on Latin America.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="91" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1.5 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Latin American Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=LATAMST 230" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="288">
<span class="code">LATAMST&#160;230</span> 
<span class="title">Cross-Listed Topics</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2009, Spring 2009, Fall 2008<br/>
This course is designed to accommodate cross-listed courses offered through other departments, the content of which is applicable to the graduate program in Latin American Studies. Content varies from course to course.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="288" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Latin American Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=LATAMST 250" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="913">
<span class="code">LATAMST&#160;250</span> 
<span class="title">Selected Topics in Latin American Studies</span> 
<span class="hours">4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2017, Fall 2016, Fall 2015<br/>
Seminar will take a multidisciplinary approach to specific geographical areas with appropriate comparative material included. Topics change each semester.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="913" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit with consent of instructor. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Latin American Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=LATAMST 292" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="530">
<span class="code">LATAMST&#160;292</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Study and Research</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Summer 2017 First 6 Week Session, Summer 2016 First 6 Week Session, Fall 2015<br/>
Directed study and research for graduate students in Latin American Studies. Primarily for graduate students engaged in an interdisciplinary exploration of Latin America-related topics in subject matter not covered in available course offerings. The course will involve directed readings and writing of a report.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="530" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of seminar per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> <br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>6 weeks - 2.5-10 hours of seminar per week<br /><span style="width: 15px; display: inline-block;"></span>8 weeks - 1.5-7.5 hours of seminar per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Latin American Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=LATAMST 298" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="372">
<span class="code">LATAMST&#160;298</span> 
<span class="title">Directed Graduate Group Study</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2017, Fall 2016, Fall 2015<br/>
Topics vary from semester to semester.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="372" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor and graduate-level standing</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 1-4 hours of independent study per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Latin American Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Letter grade. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div class="courseblock">
<p class="courseblocktitle">
<a href="/search/?P=LATAMST 299" class="btn-course" role="button" aria-controls="168">
<span class="code">LATAMST&#160;299</span> 
<span class="title">Individual Study</span> 
<span class="hours">1 - 4 Units</span>
</a>
</p>
<div class="coursebody">

<p class="courseblockdesc"><span class="descshow">Terms offered: Fall 2017, Summer 2017 8 Week Session, Fall 2016<br/>
Individual study for graduate students in Latin American Studies. Intended to provide directed reading and supervision for thesis development or special study in Latin American area.
</span><br />
</p>
<div id="168" class="coursedetails" aria-expanded="false">

<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Rules &amp; Requirements</strong></p><p><strong>Prerequisites:</strong> Consent of instructor</p><p><strong>Repeat rules:</strong> Course may be repeated for credit. Course may be repeated for credit when topic changes.</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Hours &amp; Format</strong></p><p><strong>Fall and/or spring:</strong> 15 weeks - 3 hours of lecture per week</p><p><strong>Summer:</strong> 8 weeks - 7.5 hours of lecture per week</p></div>
<div class="course-section"><p class="course-heading"><strong>Additional Details</strong></p><p><strong>Subject/Course Level:</strong> Latin American Studies/Graduate</p><p><strong>Grading:</strong> Offered for satisfactory/unsatisfactory grade only. </p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

