<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  

  
]]>
</text>
<overviewtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>From Santiago to Singapore, Berkeley offers a broad spectrum of opportunities that inspire students to think globally by living in other cultures while progressing toward their bachelors' degrees. Berkeley Study Abroad (BSA) offers a diverse array of programs across all the major disciplines in more than 40 countries. Students can enhance their undergraduate experience and gain valuable international relations skills while receiving University credit for their participation. Options include semester, year, and summer programs.</p>
<p>Many programs do not require foreign language proficiency. Financial Aid recipients qualify for financial aid assistance while abroad on BSA programs, and scholarships are available for eligible BSA students.</p>
<p>For further information, contact Berkeley Study Abroad at 160 Stephens Hall, 510-642-1356, or see the <a href="http://studyabroad.berkeley.edu">Berkeley Study Abroad</a>
 website.</p>

]]>
</overviewtext>
<berkeleystudyabroadtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>Berkeley Abroad offers a range of opportunities for students to experience other cultures while progressing toward their bachelors' degrees. </p>
<p style="margin-left:40px"><strong>UC Berkeley Summer Abroad</strong> offers intensive summer programs combined with excursions and local activities  built around Berkeley courses and led by Berkeley faculty. Find out about available <a href="http://studyabroad.berkeley.edu/summerabroad" target="_blank">countries, program options, and deadlines .</a>
</p>

<p style="margin-left:40px"><strong>The UC Berkeley Global Internships</strong> program matches students with experiential learning opportunities in a variety of countries around the world and in the San Francisco Bay Area. Students receive Berkeley credit for these programs. Find out about available <a href="http://studyabroad.berkeley.edu/globalinternships" target="_blank">countries, program options, and deadlines .</a>
</p>

]]>
</berkeleystudyabroadtext>
<uceducationabroadprogramtext>
<![CDATA[
<p>UC Education Abroad Program (UCEAP) is an expansive study abroad program that represents the entire UC system. It is one of the oldest and most reputable programs in the nation, offering summer, semester and year-long study, research, and internship abroad options. Students receive UC credit for study, research and internship programs in 42 countries worldwide.</p>
<h3>Countries/Regions</h3>
<table>
	<tbody>
		<tr>
			<td width="68">
			<h4><strong>Africa and the Middle East</strong></h4>
			<p>Botswana<br/>
			Egypt<br/>
			Ghana<br/>
			Israel<br/>
			Jordan<br/>
			Morocco<br/>
			Senegal<br/>
			South Africa<br/>
			Tanzania<br/>
			Turkey</p>
			</td>
			<td width="69">
			<h4><strong>The Americas</strong></h4>
			<p>Argentina<br/>
			Barbados<br/>
			Brazil<br/>
			Canada<br/>
			Chile<br/>
			Costa Rica<br/>
			Dominican Republic<br/>
			Mexico<br/>
			 </p>
			</td>
			<td width="69">
			<h4><strong>Asia and Oceania</strong></h4>
			<p>Australia<br/>
			China<br/>
			Hong Kong<br/>
			India<br/>
			Indonesia<br/>
			Japan<br/>
			Korea<br/>
			New Zealand<br/>
			Singapore<br/>
			Solomon Islands<br/>
			Taiwan<br/>
			Thailand<br/>
			Vietnam<br/>
			 </p>
			</td>
			<td width="69">
			<h4><strong>Europe</strong></h4>
			<p>Czech Republic<br/>
			Denmark<br/>
			France<br/>
			Germany<br/>
			Ireland<br/>
			Italy<br/>
			Netherlands<br/>
			Norway<br/>
			Russia<br/>
			Spain<br/>
			Sweden<br/>
			Switzerland<br/>
			UK, England<br/>
			UK, Scotland</p>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</tbody>
</table>
<p>For more information visit: <a href="http://studyabroad.berkeley.edu/eap" target="_blank">http://studyabroad.berkeley.edu/eap</a>
</p>

]]>
</uceducationabroadprogramtext>
<advisingtext>
<![CDATA[
<div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>Meet with a study abroad adviser for a 15-minute drop-in advising session. Advising takes place in 160 Stephens Hall on Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, and Friday, 10 to noon and 1 to 4 p.m.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>If you have questions about a specific program, visit that adviser during their drop-in hours or contact the adviser directly to request an appointment.</p>
<p>Have financial aid questions? Counselors from the Financial Aid and Scholarships Office are available in 160 Stephens Hall on Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, and Friday, 10 to noon and 1 to 4 p.m.</p>
<p>Peer advising is available in 160 Stephens Hall on Monday, Tuesday, and Thursday, 9 to 10 a.m. and 4 to 5 p.m., Wednesday 1 to 5 p.m., and Friday 9 to 10 a.m. </p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h3>Advisers</h3>
<p>Michelle Ayazi  <br/>
Countries/Programs: Botswana, Ghana, India, Ireland, Israel, Jordan, Morocco, Multi-Site (Istanbul/Florence/Barcelona, London/Paris, Rome/Istanbul), Senegal, South Africa, Tanzania, Turkey, United Kingdom Summer (Glasgow, LSE, UEA), United Kingdom (LSE, Scottish Parliament, Sotheby’s, UC Center London)<br/>
<a href="mailto:mayazi@berkeley.edu">mayazi@berkeley.edu</a>
</p>

<div class="layoutArea">
<p>Nadine Gerdes<br/>
Countries/Programs: Canada, Denmark, France, Mexico, Netherlands, Sweden, Switzerland, United Kingdom Summer (Cambridge &amp; Sussex) <br/>
<a href="mailto:nadine@berkeley.edu">nadine@berkeley.edu</a>
</p>

<p>Louise Hon<br/>
Countries/Programs: Argentina, Australia, Barbados, Brazil, Chile, Costa Rica, Dominican Republic, Multi-Site (Australia/Solomon Islands, Buenos Aires/Santiago), New Zealand, Spain<br/>
<a href="mailto:lkhon@berkeley.edu">lkhon@berkeley.edu</a>
</p>

<p>Scott McElhinney<br/>
Countries/Programs:Czech Republic, Germany, Italy, Korea, Multi-Site (Rome/Madrid), Reciprocity, Russia<br/>
<a href="mailto:scottmc@berkeley.edu">scottmc@berkeley.edu</a>
</p>

<p>Travis Pentz<br/>
Countries/Programs: China, Hong Kong, Japan, Singapore, Taiwan, Thailand, United Kingdom (English &amp; Scottish Universities, University of the Arts London)<br/>
<a href="mailto:tpentz@berkeley.edu">tpentz@berkeley.edu</a>
</p>

</div>

<div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column"> </div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="layoutArea"> </div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]>
</advisingtext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

