<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Overview</h2>
<p>The Ethnic Studies Graduate Group doctoral program focuses on the historical and sociocultural study of the core groups racialized in United States history: African Americans, Asian Americans, Chicanos and Latinos, and Native Americans. Transdisciplinary in approach, the program encourages students to adopt a broad range of theories and methods to analyze the construction of these racialized ethnocultural groups in relation to each other in the EuroAmerican context and in a transnational context.</p>
<p>As a graduate group program, courses are taught and students are advised by faculty not only from the Department of Ethnic Studies but also from other departments on campus. The core faculty consists of faculty from the Department of Ethnic Studies (composed of Asian American and Asian Diaspora Studies, Chicano Studies, and Native American Studies) and the Department of African American Studies. The affiliated faculty is composed of faculty from other departments on campus whose expertise and research interests address the concerns of comparative ethnic studies and who have expressed a special interest in working with graduate students in ethnic studies. Both core and affiliated faculty may teach courses and sit on the examination and dissertation committees of students in the Ethnic Studies Graduate Group doctoral program.</p>
<h3>Undergraduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="/archive/2015-16/undergraduate/degree-programs/asian-american-diaspora-studies/">Asian American and Asian Diaspora Studies</a>
: BA, Minor<br/>
<a href="/archive/2015-16/undergraduate/degree-programs/chicano-latino-studies/">Chicano Studies</a>
: BA, Minor<br/>
<a href="/archive/2015-16/undergraduate/degree-programs/ethnic-studies/">Ethnic Studies</a>
: BA (group major), Minor<br/>
<a href="/archive/2015-16/undergraduate/degree-programs/native-american-studies/">Native American Studies</a>
: BA, Minor</p>

<h3>Graduate Program</h3>
<p><a href="/archive/2015-16/graduate/degree-programs/ethnic-studies/">Ethnic Studies</a>
: PhD</p>

  
]]>
</text>
<coursestext>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Ethnic Studies</h3>
<div id="sc_sccoursedescs">
</div>
]]>
</coursestext>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
<h2>Faculty and Instructors</h2><h4>Faculty</h4><p class="facitem"><strong>William M. Banks, <i>Professor</i>. </strong></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Ramon Grosfoguel, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Global cities, international migration, ethnic studies, race/ethnicity, latino studies, Caribbean Studies, Latin American Studies, international comparative development, political-economy of the world-systems, urban sociology.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/14748"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>David Montejano, <i>Professor</i>. </strong>Social change, historical sociology, political sociology, community studies, race &amp; ethnic relations.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15135"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>G. Ugo Nwokeji, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Atlantic slave trade, historical demography, African history and political economy, oil and gas policy.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15355"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Laura E. Perez, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong>Chicano studies, US Latina and Latin American women&#039;s writing, Chicana/o literature, visual arts, contemporary cultural theory, Latin American women&#039;s oppositional writings.<br/><a href="http://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/node/15376"target="_blank">Research Profile</a></p><p class="facitem"><strong>Lok Siu, <i>Associate Professor</i>. </strong></p>]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

