<?xml version="1.0"?>
<courseleaf>



<text>
<![CDATA[  
<h2>Tools for Guide Content Editors</h2>
<p>Here are some resources to help you learn how to edit your content. We will continue to add new materials as they are created.</p>
<h3>Training Video</h3>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/bjscEvFEgb8" target="_blank"><strong>Berkeley Academic Guide Content Management System Training</strong></a>
 (YouTube, 36 minutes)</p>

<h3>Training Handouts</h3>
<p><strong><a href="https://drive.google.com/a/berkeley.edu/file/d/0B3xNu1bt4ND6Z1QwaWVxYVhXakk/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">Quick Toolbar and Tabs Overview</a>
</strong>
 (pdf, 2 pages, 8.5 x 11)</p>

<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/a/berkeley.edu/file/d/0B3xNu1bt4ND6Zm5Fb0FCa2ppbkk/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank"><strong>Working with Courselists</strong></a>
 (for requirements, pdf, 2 pages, 8.5 x 14-legal-size)</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://drive.google.com/a/berkeley.edu/file/d/0B3xNu1bt4ND6U1VMVmlabDJTZ0U/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank">Training for the Approvers</a>
</strong>
 (for your chairs and deans and such, pdf, 1 page, 8.5 x 11)</p>

<h3>Photo Replacement</h3>
<p>We currently offer three options if you want to replace your photo. Please keep in mind that photos need to have a strong horizontal access (two and a half times wide as high).</p>
<h5>Shutterstock (Limited Access)</h5>
<p>Each March we will have a one month paid subscription to Shutterstock. Please use the instructions in the link for more information.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://docs.google.com/a/berkeley.edu/document/d/1ekhlKyDtAiWUeOPFCG3RL0_oHU0oHN5A82h4z1MdYA8/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank">Shutterstock Option</a>
 </strong>
(google doc with image)</p>

<h5>Wikimedia (Free)</h5>
<p>This <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Main_Page" target="_blank">database</a>
 has over three million (!) freely usable media files that anyone can use. Please provide us with the link to the image you choose, and we will crop it for you (and add a credit, if necessary). When you send us the links, please indicate which page the image should go on (by providing the page url). Send images to: guide@berkeley.edu.</p>

<h5>Provide Your Own</h5>
<p>You can also provide us with your own high quality images. They need to be 1000px x 400 px x 300dpi. When you send them to us, indicate which page they should go on (by providing the page url). Send images to: guide@berkeley.edu.</p>
<h3>Contact</h3>
<p>Jenne (&quot;Jenny&quot;) Mowry, the Berkeley Academic Guide editor, is your primary contact for Guide questions.<br/>
Email: guide@berkeley.edu<br/>
Phone: 510-642-0668</p>
  
]]>
</text>
<faculty>
<![CDATA[
]]>
</faculty>
</courseleaf>

